PRANAV DHARAMTHOK

+1(971) 428-4520 dharamthokpranav@gmail.com pran4@pdx.edu

PERSONAL PROFILE

Master's student at Portland State University, passionate about software engineering with 4.5+ years of experience specializing in full-stack development, mobile application development, API design and development, data structures, and algorithms. Strong knowledge of back-end and front-end development technologies, as well as database technologies.

EDUCATION

Portland State University

Portland, OR, USA

September 2022 - Present

- M.S. in Computer Science, GPA 4.0
- · Graduate Coursework: Introduction to Web Development, Full-Stack Web Development, Software Engineering, Introduction to Database Management systems, Code Revision And Review, Analysis and Design of Algorithms.

Sant Gadge Baba Amravati University

Amravati, MH, India

July 2013 - June 2017

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering, CGPA - 7.56

EMPLOYMENT

Senior Software Developer

Pinky Promise Pvt Ltd - Mumbai, India

March 2021 - August 2022

- (Contract)
- Developed full-Stack projects, REST APIs, back-end business logic, complex algorithms, and scheduling functions that run on specific time intervals.
- · Implemented modules like Chat-bot, Chatroom, and E-commerce along with communication APIs which are Twilio, and
- Learned data transmission and network protocols, designing high-quality software and architecture.

Senior Software Developer

Austere Systems Pvt Ltd - Pune, India

March 2019 - March 2021

- · Developed highly functional full-Stack projects in MEAN, REST APIs, complex back-end logic algorithms, API authentication and security.
- Involved in designing and developing of hybrid mobile applications in Flutter and Ionic Framework.
- Handled Team-Lead position successfully and ensured all projects are completed in time and to company specifications.
- Learned and Involved in task prioritizing, planning and estimation, creating user flows and prototypes.

Software Associate

Kaldin Solutions - Pune, India

November 2017 - February 2019

- Developed customized and highly functional CRM systems in JAVA along with integration of third-party APIs which are SMS and Email Gateways, Google Maps, Directions API, etc.
- Developed new functionalities, and technologies and integrate them into existing functions.
- Involved in software development, assisted the development team and manager with all aspects of software designing and coding, support, analysis, and all related activities.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SASS, SCSS
- Web Development Technologies: MEAN Stack, MERN Stack, Node.js, React.js, Angular, Express.js
- Hybrid Mobile Development Technologies: Ionic Framework, Flutter
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Cloud Technologies: AWS EC2, AWS RDS, Horeku
- Tools: Xcode, Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ etc.

PROJECTS

Academic Projects

- Click-N-Split: This is a bill-splitting project which is created using React and Node.js that allows us to upload and take a picture of a store receipt. It provides detailed receipt content in a tabular format. Additionally, it offers the choice of selecting personal and group items and sending an email with an individual share amount.
- Chatx: This is a chat application that is developed using React and Node. js that allow users to create a private chatroom, invite other users via an invite link, and send emails.

Professional Projects

- **Genuine Tracking Solutions (GTS):** Developed a JAVA Project along with an Ionic Framework application that tracks logistics vehicles and trucks in real-time on the google map and keeps the record in the MySQL database. Reports were generated in pdf and sent via email from the dashboard.
- Model School Application: In Ionic Framework, it was developed for two different modules, Model School Students and Model School Staff. Users can interact with various school modules, such as Attendance, Examination, Schedules, Library Management, Fees and Challans, Assignments, Circulars, Leave, etc.
- MarkeTop CRM: Developed in MEAN Stack, it features an automation feature that converts contacts into leads through NodeJS algorithm when certain predefined criteria are met. Emails and SMS and Phone Call services are implemented with Twilio API along with their scheduling and sequencing which can be configured to run according to specific time intervals.
- **Pinky Promise:** Using NodeJS and React Native and MongoDB, this app gathers symptoms in the form of responses from women and diagnoses of diseases. Among the features of this app are chatrooms where women can anonymously discuss issues such as pregnancy, periods, and fertility with other women, send prescription requests to doctors, and book pathology tests if necessary.